the nether update is here we are
officially in 1.16 and i can't zoom so
i'm gonna have to do the poor man zoom
[Music]
there we go
that's the best i can do it is 1.16 time
and we are heading
to the nether
so much is now possible with 1.16 and i
even got some of the stuff together to
do some crafting and show you we now
have soul campfires
soul torches
chains and soul lanterns my base was
designed
specifically with these kind of blocks
in mind is this a different kind of
campfire now that i think about it if i
reignite this oh yeah it is there's two
different kinds of campfire and they're
pretty indistinguishable when they're
put out that's interesting but this
means some slight decoration differences
are gonna have to be made for example
we'll get rid of these which don't
really fit
we'll hang a couple of torches we will
then hang a couple of soul lanterns and
all of a sudden my mansion just got 10
times spookier
that makes such a huge difference we
need to get rid of that
every time i get rid of all the posters
they come straight back again no bad
scar there we go now all i have to do is
replace them all over the mansion and
this will fit in
perfectly and also while i was between
episodes i did quite a substantial
amount of work over here
tidying up the hole that i started and i
did actually time lapse this very
quickly so
let's uh let's show what that looked
like i did have to use a lot of tnt
again
[Music]
and this is the result and unfortunately
i have actually mega failed i i failed
because i actually wanted to get this
part of the base finished
before 1.16 arrived i was meant to move
my nether portal from up there
to over here and i have a really really
cool plan for it the only issue is yeah
mining out a lot of blocks takes a huge
amount of time
so i think i'll have to come back to
this
a little later on and it might be next
episode that we managed to install our
nether portal but for now what we're
going to do
is head straight over to the shopping
district because
it is
vote time and it is the last day
and grumba better have something to tell
us that's uh gonna save us because
mumbo's not doing too well in the polls
uh
i for su somehow i forgot that this was
the nether update
and there's no nether portal or nether
hub or anything here oh my goodness this
is squelchy squelchy squelchy look at
his mustaches on the back wait until he
turns around how has he not seen me
i didn't make him jump as much as i
thought well he's managed to link up his
portal now i gotta do mine in theory
this is our portal and i have no way of
labeling this so i'm gonna put a
campfire here so i know it's mine
success
okay now let's head over to the shopping
district which is what we were supposed
to be doing but i just realized i
don't there's no hub at all you know
what it might be quicker if we just fly
in the overworld let's fly over now and
see if we can meet mumbo
and sort out what's going on with
grumbot i i can't zoom in on you anymore
i know you seem so far away these end
rods are actually way further away than
i ever thought they were i know there's
there's actually a way if you go to
options put your fov 30 it's like poor
man zoom in
and it's really shaky wait hang on i
always have to put this
there
[Laughter]
hi mambo
all right well should we just record
this whole segment just fully zoomed in
the whole time oh no it's too difficult
it's too it doesn't it's too it does
make me feel a bit ill
right grumbot has been i i i see that
you've already been here but grumbot has
been hacked he's been taken over yeah i
mean it does look adorable like it does
it
is very cute but i do think we need to
take him back to his former glory and
i mean i've tried my best to unhack him
and i you know i've done the internals
and things like that and
things seem better i tried to fix him
too i just got him stuck on get green
yeah no i didn't get gorgeous he was
stuck on get gorgeous so i got some
progress
but don't let me ever touch this sort of
thing ever again well yeah i mean yeah
so i managed to fix the get green
problem um i yeah it's fixed okay you
don't sound too confident no yeah it's
it's it's fixed i mean it'll be
interesting to see how things go okay i
got loads of these uh i got loads of the
banners back so we should put him back
to his his former glory
and then uh and then and then we'll ask
him what's that what's up because it is
actually vote day by the way it's it is
time to vote so it is actually this is
this is when the rubber hits the road
this is when we actually really so
hopefully has some really good advice
because we're not doing so well in the
fall
absolutely
spectacular advice yeah
his long term plan is gonna is gonna hit
there we go looking all handsome again
he is looking a lot better back to his
usual self now we have to ask him like
last minute yeah
pull something out the bag forgotten to
revise for your test like doing your
homework that morning
yeah right this is uh eating breakfast
and doing my homework yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah what do i ask him um it is
vote day that seems important to tell
him i wonder if he yeah he might just
not know i mean he might have been kind
of out of commission for a few days he's
probably doing a hard reboot i'm just
gonna put help in capital letters after
that all right oh my goodness okay let's
go
[Music]
come on grumble you better pull
something out the bag here because we're
like in fact following your instructions
has made our polls worse
what is love does anything really matter
what is anger am i loved or used he's
having an existential crisis what if it
was all a dream do i have control am i
good what if our world is not ours oh no
if i make mumbo mare am i there oh
there's smoke coming out the top of his
head what
oh he's officially melted
oh we've melted them why must my life
make me ache jeez oh my god he's he's
gone he's been sending a lot of he's
been sending a lot of the same message
they're still coming out too fast but is
he oh my goodness oh
he's just been saying goodbye dads
goodbye dance oh god oh dear this is not
i think this is not a good situation i
mean i've got i've got almost two stacks
of goodbye dance on me i've got one and
a half stacks of goodbye i think i think
we killed him yeah granbot's gone i mean
he's asking what are all these feelings
why is my head hurting
oh blessings are my thoughts just a tool
i am granbot yet i am dads this i know
so much yet so little are my creators
happy for me yes are there others like
me what is love
does anything really matter
he's he's had a full breakdown and it's
good
we failed you you didn't fail us grumbot
we have failed
i mean he did he did bet he did fail he
didn't eat faith
if any if anything you were more popular
if you did nothing at all
yes yeah um yes
100 but that doesn't mean that
it didn't have to end like this no no it
didn't what do we do now i mean it's the
last day dude yeah i mean we gotta go
and vote really haven't we yeah probably
do you need to do that yeah should we
head over to the shopping district i
don't think crombots
yeah i mean okay i think it would be it
would actually be rude to ask him
something else
he's clearly not not really open to
questions right now so when you say you
fixed him
i mean i fixed him maybe a little bit
too well
like i think i think he's been just
struck with the realities of life all at
once yeah i think he made him too smart
oh man all right well um let's go let's
let's let's let's get rid of this and uh
we'll head over to the shopping district
shall we oh what's
hell yeah that's what you've seen that's
what i was just about to say yeah we've
got a giant scar head i'm gonna have to
do a poor man zoom there we go i was
about to say i also i went to zoom in
and then couldn't uh that's a jelly and
a scar in a mountain there
this looks this looks very cool i mean
this has definitely improved the area
next to
next to the the town hall voting for
scar will bring trees reeds but spelled
read reads wrong so we know scott wrote
this
scar will bring trees reads cats and
beautiful land
oh wait well he's promising a lot more
than me and he's got road designs he's
got a plan oh man he's got mumbo he's
got the one thing grumbot didn't give us
a plan
you know we had no idea what i was going
to do if i actually became mayor and um
option one that's pretty nice i kind of
like option two
i mean even road option three is pretty
nice as well any of these would be what
we've currently got going on in the
shopping district to be honest
yeah and then he's he's also got the
trees and the terrain
there's a b-dubs there's a b-dubs hidden
in the corner they're all covered
i mean this is yeah this doesn't make me
feel good
so and he's and he's running for mayor
yeah and he's he's accepting votes and
it's voting today and he's got this
built okay okay and he's got options and
people can see what okay um
what
so
i can't i can't really comment on that
oh yeah it is it's open today opens june
23rd that is today so we can all we can
all go in and i guess we've got to vote
for dog catcher as well okay i mean how
does how does one do this what do you
just do you just just go into the booth
yeah you go into the booth there's some
paper in that chest
okay i'll make sure not to throw in an
extra
i'm gonna vote for i think therefore i
am but i am not
okay well
i mean i'll leave this in private yeah a
bit of a private moment so i'll uh i'll
catch you catch you later then dude i
think i know you're gonna vote for dog
catcher though yeah i mean you know
there's only really one there's one
option there's one option it's the best
option so i think i think we've got that
covered i think we can both say who
we're voting for there all right i'll uh
i'll see you later right now we have to
vote i guess i've actually got some
paper here i'll just uh i'll rename one
of these so here's the thing grambot
kind of
melted and i'm not gonna lie
seeing mount scarmore and those options
has
really made me think that mumbo may not
be up to the task as much as i've
enjoyed
shouting mumbo for mayor
at
everything and everyone
now that i've actually seen that there's
an option for nice trees a nice nice
pass and greenery everywhere in the
shopping district just let's let's just
not tell mumbo okay that i i'm
i'm voting scar
i i think scar will actually make a
really
a really good mayor he's gonna re he's
it's done it's too late i can't back out
of it now
it
it is done i
don't
oh my goodness i'm such a traitor but
it's for the good of the shopping
district and the server that scar
becomes mare i think like look at all
the paths they're such a mess
scar will
make this place absolutely
amazing i mean look at his shop look
even look at mount scarmore if we had
those sorts of paths everywhere and i'm
hoping he'll get rid of the mycelium not
sure mumbo would have done that all
right
now we gotta vote for dog catcher hmm
who do i who do i vote for dog catcher
ya
joe hills there we go i think i think i
know who's gonna win that one right so
when we have all of the answers what
we're gonna do
is we're gonna display it here so in
fact i think what we should do is
actually reset these all to zero
at the moment it looks like the
forerunner is stress
followed oh actually equal with stress
and false
and then scar just be behind and we're
dead last we are dead last so let's
reset all of these
to zero
and then the results can be put here
when they're all in
there we go all reset ready for the
final results i hope
i hope mumbo's not mad with me i'm sure
i'm sure we'll be fine it'll be
it'll be fine
it's fine ow anyway let's head back to
the base captain rose barrel yeah well
you know since he's probably not going
anywhere welcome to the barge please buy
he's like he's like my shopping
assistant what should we call this
villager give me some names in the
comments
all right let's head back to the base
actually i'm not gonna make it to the
base on these rockets
this is why we have emergency rockets
well we've made it back to the base
i feel kind of bad about voting for scar
but also it feels like the right
decision
now in memory of grumbot i want to keep
one of these on display
as a memento
of our dear grumbot friend and while
we're here
i have crafted up
a bunch of chains which i am going to
put in the green emporium to sell they
are they they do kind of count as
something that you wouldn't necessarily
farm a lot of and i'm gonna do the same
with soul lanterns and soul campfires
it's just gonna take a little while to
do so but before we do any more crafting
or anything like that i think what we're
going to do is actually head to the
nether and just take a look around we're
going to try and find a place for our
nether project i have a secret very
secret nether project in mind that i
don't really want to share
just yet
but we need to look for a good place
here we are
in the spookiest part of the game now
there's two things that i really want to
do one
grab some netherright two
find a place for my secret project the
atmosphere in here is absolutely
nuts i've actually kind of forgotten
what the nether was actually like simply
because we've been standing on the top
of it for so long
now i did try out a lot of this in
snapshots very early on but i kind of
stopped because i wanted at least some
of it to be a bit of a surprise now the
big thing to find is of course never
right
wow
okay there's some piglins over there i
think we should just try and gather as
much stuff as possible
whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa what did i do
to you
what did i do
oh they're fast
i thought piglens were cool with you
until they're not do they like golden
carrots
oh they do
they love golden carrots that is
adorable i feel like i'm just
discovering all of this stuff i probably
should have read up on this update
before i just waltzed in here it's more
fun this way though so we got zombie
piglins and they're not bothered but
normal piglins they're not they're not
happy with us
what if you want gold gold gold take the
gold take the gold no
take the gold carrots gold carrots
there we go
i can't believe they love they love gold
whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa
no no take more gold carrots lola listen
listen listen listen listen listen
listen here
we can be friends
oh so they just get distracted by it
i see i see i see
okay so we're now
flying through the nether
trying to find a really nice place for
my secret project and it's really a
toss-up between
this biome like the bluey one
or the red one i think the red one might
be slightly better for my project oh my
goodness
now that's wacky okay these are pretty
cool free standing i mean i guess
they're just a bit like scaffolding but
we'll take some of these
oh my goodness i forgot about these
crazy crazy creatures how do i get
one of those poor man zoom how do i get
me one of those i imagine that i'm gonna
need a saddle for one of those and i did
not bring one let's continue our hunt
particularly for netherrite which means
i think we gotta dig down
oh wow that was loud
and i made it into a basil i think the
basalt one might be a contender for the
secret nether project this is one of the
blocks i have been most excited to get
my hands on
and equally
another one that we want to get our
hands on blackstone
what an absolutely gorgeous looking
block
you're gonna have to excuse the pun but
i think it's gonna take a lot of soul
searching to get the exact location for
my nether base
okay i think we are now far enough away
from anything build related in terms of
the nether hub
to go and get some nether right
so some of you will know what netherrite
is others will probably not
and some of you will probably know more
than me
no no no no no no no no no no no no no
no no no
whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa
oh my goodness that was not a fun
adventure
how did i almost flew in here as well
what we have just experienced in here is
a box of pain a box of pain and panic oh
my goodness i think i nearly had a heart
attack okay
all right let's just take a breath
okay so netherrite is what we can
upgrade our diamond armor and tools to
and they are
lava proof that's the biggest thing
about them and they're more durable and
better in every single way
but to get them they are extremely rare
and you've got to dig down to about why
level 15
to to find any or i think they're most
they're most prevalent at why level 15.
of course we will come across lots of
lava pockets but i've come sl ever so
slightly prepared for this mining
session what we're going to do is make a
big long line and use a ve
okay i think that's a sign and we're
gonna we are going to use the tnt that i
brought with me
i've actually invested a huge amount in
this remember how expensive tnt is and
we are going
to make a big big boom because tnt is so
expensive we also want to be really
really efficient with this so we'll make
one long line there
and we'll probably make one long line
here no no no no no okay lava definitely
travels like 10 times faster now
okay okay okay
okay maybe we'll make a line this side
no no no no no we're not
oh man okay lava is so much more panic
inducing
the fact that we haven't even come
across oh i was just about to say we
haven't even come across one but there
it is
here it is the ancient debris this is
the block that we are after it is
exceptionally rare now we don't want to
waste the tnt too much so try and spread
it out
as much as possible we want to be
this isn't this isn't even the most
efficient way of doing it i just want to
see if we can get a few ancient debris
doing this
okay this may be using up most of my tnt
so i'm very very very very hopeful that
this has some effect
okay
i think i think i'm ready
so three
two
one ancient debris
run away run away run away
oh there was one right there
oh this is work to treat
this is
fairly efficient
i must admit oh no
somehow i didn't make it either way i
can't help but feel that was kind of
worth it i mean this is literally the
rarest material in the game don't go in
the lava
no no
stop coming in the lava
i'm not sure i like the nether that much
we've got to be super careful
we currently got
that's that's number four
that's five and six oh my goodness and
three up there this this material right
here is like i'm not sure how many times
more but it is more rare than diamonds
and you might actually be wondering
oh
is is netherright going to become the
new currency
well that actually just depends on
whose shop it is like i'm personally not
going to be charging netherright for my
items we might have got all of the ones
so far
so
let's do a quick
let's ignite the rest of this tnt
because this was definitely a huge huge
success
there it goes
the problem is the lava
oh
man okay there's neither right
there is never right
but it's gonna be a bit of a challenge
to get to it i think the more
netherright you can get the better
okay we need to play that more safe in
the future
in the future more safe
i think i could title this video no not
in the lava
so we got a grand total of 12 ancient
debris not too bad but also incredibly
expensive so now
i'm going to basically either mine my
way for more netherright or blow it up
either way let's do it time lapse style
here we go
[Music]
[Applause]
oh
boy
by my calculations i am directly above
my nether portal
now what i did was i mined 2 000 blocks
all the way back to the portal and
before i continue this conversation let
me get out of here safely because i i'm
a little bit concerned that there's
going to be lava somewhere along the way
oh there is
i'm so used to encounter oh
that was close i am so
used to encountering lava now and it
moves so quickly in the nether honestly
really fast i made it back there were
some major major close calls but we made
it back to the base
let's take quick stock of what happened
so these are all the materials that i
ended up getting in the first bit i did
tnt mining and it took no time at all 20
minutes and i got 25 ancient debris i
then spent over an hour mining back to
my portal and i only got 12 debris
that's not a lot
and and then along the way i also got as
much basalt and other things that i
could get my hands on so all in all a
pretty successful trip now the moment
that i've really been looking forward to
37 ancient debris let's smelt this up
and get my armor upgraded i think you've
got to combine it with gold in order to
get the netherite ingot so let's give
this a go if i put these together
no
no how how does this go how do you craft
this oh right
oh it's even more expensive than i
thought it's four netherright scrap and
then four gold ingots that entire
two-hour session
got me nine ingots
just nine
that is uh
way less than i thought i would get the
next option would be
yeah okay here it is
upgrade gear
oh thank goodness it keeps it keeps all
the enchantments
oh my goodness another right sword maybe
i should do all the other bits first
oh this is amazing never right helmet
never right leggings never right boots
okay let's be sensible axe
and shovel that's everything and i've
got one spare it's kept all the
enchantments let's see how i look
whoa
very purple looking i look like thanos i
kind of look like panels
i'm not i'm not gonna lie to you
i feel pretty decked out like this is
this is pretty sweet
oh my goodness okay we gotta go flex
we're gonna go flex let's where's mumbo
this sword does 11 damage
let's try it let's try it on a little
creeper
they didn't one shot him oh where is he
i'm here to flex yeah check it check it
mumbo
check it check it out he's not saying
anything but he's jealous
i've never felt so bad having diamond
armor it's so true i this is such a huge
step for minecraft with my experiment in
mind what we need to do
is actually go straight over to the
shopping district and definitely charge
more for the tnt like we got literally
double
no my portal does not look as cool as
yours
not yet
while we're there it would be a really
good opportunity to do this add these to
the barge and i'm also gonna craft up
those other things that i talked about
at the start of the episode now we all
know that with haste 2 on the beacon
you can get insta mine
but i'm curious to see if it's actually
possible to get it any faster with a
netherright pickaxe it's going to be
very strange getting used to the fact
that diamond is not the best
and having to say diamond pickaxe and
everything i'm probably going to call
netherright diamond at some point just
out of sheer habit
i'll be honest with you i don't think
this is that much faster if it is it's
very very fractional i mean there's not
a lot faster than instant is there to be
honest with you but things like coal and
iron ore they definitely feel a lot
faster the other thing is that
netherrite is supposed to not burn
in lava
now
this sounds like the sort of thing your
friend tells you to make you burn your
items
so i'm um i'm pretty skeptical i don't
actually know whether this is going to
work or not so let's try it with a
pickaxe because at least i've got two of
those
in theory it should float come on yes
okay there wasn't it wasn't a lie
you're if you die in lava at least you
get your stuff back provided you can get
over the lava
that is amazing okay i've got everything
together i've got the soul campfires
which i want to sell seoul lanterns and
chains so let's head over to the barge
and take all of this with us okay so we
need to stock all this up
and let's see if anyone's cottoned on to
my tnt thing we need to reprice this
like heavily tnt is basically diamonds
now
and i need to i need to get that hiked
up right away
and oh and the same with tnt hello just
gonna quickly
hike this price up
um so it is now
oh goodness what do i do one diamond
three diamonds
for one stack
yep three diamonds for one stack it is
now gold dust while the netherright rush
is going we need to capitalize
capitalize capitalize capitalize i think
mumbo might have the same idea as me
i think i i think mumbo's on to it hold
on we're gonna change this we need to
change this to 11 diamonds for one stack
boom
we gotta capitalize on this netherright
rush
he's absolutely gobsmacked well it's
true it is absolutely true
all of this tnt
hear me out all of this tnt would
probably get you a stack of netherrite
and netherright is really really
expensive and rare so while the
netherright rushes in
tnt's got to be expensive
real expensive
unbelievable
i can do you a deal five stacks of tnt
tell you what one two three four five
six
31 diamonds 31 diamonds completely
arbitrary that's still a really good
deal by the way that is that is a that
is a heck of a deal
done sold
there you go
enjoy your netherrite
when people realize how valuable tnt is
gonna be simply because of how fast it
means you can get netherrite they are
going to be piling in the shop i got i
literally got here just in time
likewise to be fair i did change the
price right in front of mumbo so
he paid
i think
about five or six diamonds per stack
which is only a couple of diamonds over
so i basically gave him uh the old price
just a little bit more expensive but i
think i think given the value of tnt has
now skyrocketed it's a fairly it's a
fairly good deal
you know i haven't actually checked the
barge i i didn't bother i was so busy
trying to pike up the price of tnt i
forgot to actually check the sales and
and you know what
we have done really well people are
buying
all sorts of things
you know what i've changed my mind on
the sand that's really that's really too
expensive
really really too expensive
so i think realistically it should be
one diamond for one stack i got too
excited by mumbo being there i think
that's that's more fair okay
that's it i'm pretty i'm pretty pleased
look at how the barge
has evolved and
become a real place to get all of your
items that you need man we gotta we got
a lot done today everyone and i'm afraid
we are definitely out of time so today
we have visited grumbot we unfortunately
witnessed him melting we then went ahead
and we voted for scar in the election
hopefully he does become mayor although
of course i wouldn't be upset if mumbo
also made it for mayor you know
wouldn't be a bad thing but
it was this i gotta admit it was this it
was the promise of new roads that did it
for me
and of course we got netherrite we did
some experimenting with gathering
netherright
and boy we've just we've got a lot to do
we also did a little bit of work to the
base okay that's it for me everyone
thank you very much for watching i hope
you enjoyed this episode and good
bye